Sometimes love is stranger than fiction.
Watching the Detectives is a comedy, romance film directed by Paul Soter.
Neil, a self-proclaimed film geek and owner of Gumshoe video, has always been
content to live vicariously through his favorite films noir.
But when he meets Violet, a real-life femme fatale, his mundane world gets turned upside
down and the line between reality and the movies quickly begins to blur.
Neil, played by Cillian Murphy.
Violet, played by Lucy Liu.
Jonathan, played by Jason Sudeikis.
Lucien, played by Michael Panes.
Marcia, played by Callie Thorne.
Buddy, played by Michael Yurchak.
Watching the Detectives is a 2007 American romantic comedy film written and
directed by Paul Soter in his feature directorial debut.
The film stars Cillian Murphy as the film geek owner of an independent video rental store
whose life is upended when he meets a thrill-seeking femme fatale (Lucy Liu).
The film had its world premiere at the Tribeca Film Festival on May 1, 2007,
and was released on DVD in the United States on August 12, 2008.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.